无敌浩克
危险
爆炸振动校园
卡弗大学实验室发生神秘事故
看到绿色怪物
在现场发现实验室设备
目标逃脱追捕
目击绿色大脚野人
征用请求  美国陆军  斯塔克工业
批准
斯塔克工业
伊丽莎白·罗斯博士
班纳企图与其取得联系  2006年2月7日
通讯被拦截
寻人继续
尼克·弗瑞
神盾局局长
已知联络人
伊丽莎白·罗斯博士
前女友
L·参森博士
罗斯博士同事
精神病学家
"里克"理查德·琼斯
学生
罗斯  他在外面做什么
他停止逃跑了吗
五个月里无人目击
无事故天数
巴西罗西尼亚贫民窟
好了吗
Is it ready?
简装葡萄牙语字典
这一拳很棒
That's a great punch.
饿了吗
饿了
我们来锻炼你的呼吸
这里  情绪
恐惧不好  情绪和控制
Fear no good. So emotion and control.
用你的膈膜
控制你愤怒的最佳办法
就是控制你的身体
控制你的脉搏
呼吸  呼吸
Breathe. Breathe.
呼吸
等等
Wait.
好了
Okay.
我可以让它撑一阵  但你得
I can make it work for a while, but you need...
我需要一座新工厂
好吧
Okay. Okay.
五个月来你一直这么帮我忙
你这么聪明不该做零工
让我给你份固定的工资吧
不不不  关掉生产线  关机
No, no, no. Shut that off! Turn it off!
小心
Watch out!
好了
Okay!
巴西至美国
你想跟我一起吃午饭吗
滚蛋  外国佬
你有什么问题吗
太迟了
别惹我...饿[生气]
你不会喜欢我
饿了[生气]时的样子
说错了
That's not right.
你啊
Oh, you.
看到了吗
You see that? See that?
这是我离开这里的机会
My ticket out of here.
加密中
已加密
呼叫 蓝先生
{\an8\b1\c&H6EB6AD&\1a&H00&蓝      你在吗?
蓝先生:
绿先生!
很高兴再次收到你的消息,
我神秘的朋友!
我找到了
终于啊
真是漂亮的小花  是吧
务必用大剂量的
祝你好运
该死
Goddamn it!
又失败了
你用了多少?
全部
那我们该见面了
不安全
携带伽马毒素才不安全呢
别去找花了
给我寄一份血液样本来
你不让我帮忙我就帮不了你
绿先生
蓝先生  美国  纽约市
弗吉尼亚州 阿灵顿
这个挺有意思的
Here's something a bit more interesting.
可能是伽马中毒
It's a possible gamma sickness.
在密尔沃基州
Milwaukee.
一男子饮下瓜拉纳汽水
A man drank one of those guarana sodas.
但汽水的劲头比他料想的要大
Guess it had a little more kick than he was looking for.
在哪进行装瓶的
Where was it bottled?
巴西  弗德港
Porto verde, Brazil.
派我们的特工和手下
Get our agents and people
去那家装瓶场找一个白人男子
looking for a white man at the bottling plant.
告诉他们不得接触
Tell them no contact!
他看到他们的影子就会跑掉
If he even sees them, he's gone!
大沼泽地约翰逊堡
我尽可能替你找了人
I got you who I could.
时间紧促  但他们都是好兵
Short notice, but they're all quality.
我还给你找了个王牌
And I pulled you one Ace.
埃米尔·布朗斯基
Emil Blonsky.
生于俄罗斯  在英国长大
Born in Russia, raised in England.
是英国皇家海军陆战队借给美国特种作战司令部的
And on loan to socom from the royal marines.
我知道你为此搭了不少人情  乔
I know you cashed in some chips for this, Joe.
很高兴我能帮忙
Glad I could help.
别浪费机会
Just make it good.
这是目标和地点
This is the target and the location.
抓活的
Snatch and grab, live capture.
你们将拿到麻醉镖弹夹和压制武器
You'll have your dart clips and suppression ordnance,
实弹仅限备用
but live fire is for backup only.
那里有当地人  要做得严密低调
We got local out there, but we want it tight and quiet.
他很能打吗
Is he a fighter?
目标是美国政府的逃犯
Your target is a fugitive from the us government
他盗取了军事机密
who stole military secrets.
他还涉嫌与两名科学家  一名军官
He is also implicated in the deaths of two scientists,
一名爱达荷州州警  可能还有
a military officer, an Idaho state trooper
两名加拿大猎人的死有关
and possibly two Canadian hunters.
所以别等着看他能不能打
So don't wait to see if he's a fighter!
麻醉他  带他回来
Tranq him and bring him back.
加密中
已加密
来电
蓝先生:
好消息
初步血检表明  伽马含量显著减少
这能治好我吗?
但是
我需要更多数据
拜托
Oh, come on.
我需要更多数据
接触程度
伽马浓度
细胞饱和度
不可能  数据不在这里
那在哪里
在家
摄像机
Camera.
开始了
Here we go.
摆脱那只狗
Get rid of the damn dog.
抓住他
Take him!
目标跑了
Target's on the move.
他在哪
Where is he?
他在街上
He's on the ground.
我们走
Let's go!
走
Go!
快跑
Move, move!
谢谢
上
Go, go, go!
快走
Go! Go!
让开
Clear everyone out!
别跟丢了
Do not lose him!
不
No!
绕到他后面去
Get around behind him!
目标经过了抓捕车090
Target moving past mobile unit 0-9-0.
不
Oh, no.
开什么玩笑
You got to be kidding me.
-他在哪  -已发现目标
- Where is he? - Target acquired.
外国佬
Gringo!
走
Let's go.
不
No!
不要
Please! No!
别拿我电脑
Not the computer!
还给我
Gimme that!
不要
No!
现在不那么厉害了吧
再耍那些花哨的招数啊
来啊
停手吧  求你
我  生气
会非常糟糕
你生气糟糕  外国佬
You bad angry, g?
我生气才糟糕呢
I very bad angry.
不
Oh, no.
你不懂
You don't understand!
马上要发生非常糟糕的事了
Something really bad is about to happen here!
是啊  非常糟
你们看到了吗
Anybody else seeing this?
有某种不明物体  请指示
We've got a bogey of some kind. Please advise.
那就是目标  把麻醉镖都打出去
That is the target! Use every tranq you've got!
马上
Do it now!
撤  撤  撤
Go live! Go live! Go live!
-快走  -快跑
- Move! - Get out of the way!
不
No!
它在我们后面  快走
It's behind us! Move! Move!
开火
Get him!
打他  开火
Shoot him. Shoot him!
离我远点
Leave me alone.
不
No! No!
我开枪之前就知道情况不对
I knew something was different before I got the shot off.
这是他跑掉之前身上带着的
He had it on him when he bolted.
那是他女朋友吗
Is that a girlfriend?
或许她在帮他
She helps him, maybe?
她已经不牵涉其中了
She is no longer a factor.
我们早就断绝了他们的往来  他是一个人
We closed that door to him a long time ago. He's alone.
他想一个人待着
He wants to be alone.
但查查看他有没有跟人联络
But see if he's been talking to anybody.
请原谅  长官
Forgive me, sir?
难道没人想谈谈
Doesn't anybody want to talk about
刚刚发生的情况吗
what went down in there? 'Cause...
他没有甩掉我们
He didn't lose us.
他也不是一个人  长官
And he was not alone, sir.
我们都围住他了
We had him.
然后我们被什么袭击了
And then something hit us, something...
很大块头的东西
Something big hit us!
他把叉车当垒球一般丢
It threw a forklift truck like it was a softball!
那是我见过的最强大的东西
It was the most powerful thing I've ever seen.
它跑了
Well, it's gone.
如果班纳知道它是什么
Well, if Banner knows what it is,
我要找到他
I'm gonna track him down,
拿我的脚踩着他的喉咙
I'm gonna put my foot on his throat
-然后  -那就是班纳
- and I'm gonna... - That was Banner.
它
It
就是班纳
was Banner.
你得解释这句话  长官
You have to explain that statement, sir.
不  我不用
No, I don't.
你干得很好
You've done a good job.
收拾东西  带我们的人上飞机
Pack up and get our men on a plane.
我们回家
We're going home.
无事故天数
等等
Wait.
拜托
Please.
可以帮我吗
我不会说葡萄牙语
我在哪
Where am I?
危地马拉
我要去附近小镇
可以帮帮我吗
上车吧
来  披上这个
你要去哪
回家
我以前也曾在糟糕的任务中遭遇危险
I've run into bad situations on crap missions before.
我眼见好人牺牲
I've seen good men go down
就因为有人
purely because someone
不肯把情况如实告诉我们
didn't let us know what we were walking into.
但我继续下次任务
I've moved on to the next one,
因为这是我们的工作  是吧
because that's what we do, right?
职责如此
I mean, that's the job.
但这次
But this?
这是全新境界的奇怪
This is a whole new level of weird.
我不想就此不管
And I don't feel inclined to step away from it.
如果你要再去抓他  我加入
So if you're taking another crack at him, I want in.
恕我直言
And, with respect,
你应该找支准备充分  可以开战的队伍
you should be looking for a team that's prepped and ready to fight,
如果那玩意再次出现
because if that thing shows up again,
会有很多职业硬汉
you're gonna have a lot of professional tough guys
吓尿裤子
pissing in their pants.
长官
Sir.
墨西哥恰帕斯
有弹力更大的吗
Tienes més stretchy'?
嗯  完美
Yeah. Perfecto.
我要强调  我即将跟你说的
Let me emphasize that what I'm about to share with you
对于我个人和军队都非常敏感
is tremendously sensitive, both to me personally and the army.
你知道我们有
You're aware that we've got an
步兵武器开发项目
infantry weapons development program.
二战期间  他们启动了一项子项目
Well, in WWII, they initiated a subprogram
做生物科技力量强化
for bio-tech force enhancement.
超级士兵
Yeah, super soldier.
对
Yes.
虽然说得过于简单了  但没错
An oversimplification, but yes.
我把它翻了出来
And I dusted it off,
让他们认真研究了起来  大胆的研究
got 'em doing serious work again, bold work.
所有人都在努力增强士兵的装备
Across the hall, they were trying to arm you better.
而我们是想增强士兵本身
We were tryin' to make you better.
班纳的工作当时还在初期
Banner's work was very early phase.
甚至不涉及到武器应用
It wasn't even weapons application.
他以为他在研究辐射抗性
He thought he was working on radiation resistance.
我根本不会告诉他项目的真相
I wouId never have toId him what the project reaIIy was.
但他对自己的发现非常确信
But he was so sure of what he was onto,
于是拿自己做了测试
that he tested it on himself.
结果出了大岔子
And something went very wrong.
要么就是非常成功
Or it went very right.
在我看来
As far as I'm concerned,
他的身体都是美军的资产
that man's whole body is the property of the us army.
你说他没打算研发武器  是吧
You said he wasn't working on weapons, right?
-对  -但你是在研发武器  是吧
- No. - But you were. You were, weren't you?
你还试了别的东西
You were trying other things.
我们研发的一种血清
One serum we developed
非常有前景
was very promising.
他为什么跑了
So why did he run?
他是个科学家
He's a scientist.
他不是我们的人
He is not one of us.
布朗斯基  你多大  45吗
Blonsky, how old are you? 45?
39.
催人老啊  是吧
It takes a toll, doesn't it?
是啊
Yes, it does.
那就离开战壕吧
So get out of the trenches.
凭你的记录  该当上上校了
You should be a colonel by now, with your record.
不  我是个战士
No, I'm a fighter.
只要可以  我会一直战斗下去
I'll be one for as long as I can.
如果我可以把现在的经验
You know, if I could take what I know now,
放进我10年前的身体里
put it in the body I had ten years ago,
那会是个我不会想对付的人
that would be someone I wouldn't want to fight.
这我或许能安排
I could probably arrange something like that.
弗吉尼亚州 卡弗大学
无事故天数
伊丽莎白·罗斯博士      细胞生物学
斯坦利披萨
保重  孩子们
Take care, kids.
停止营业
斯坦  我保证
Stan, I give you my word,
不管你听说了我什么事  都不是真的
whatever you've heard about me, it's not true.
我知道  我一直知道
I know it. I always knew it.
你知道我怎么看你俩
I mean, you know how I felt about you two.
你跟她谈过了吗
Have you talked to her?
没有
No.
她不知道我来了
She doesn't know that I'm here.
她有男朋友了
She's with somebody?
他是个心理医生
Yeah, he's a head shrink.
据说是最厉害的之一  但人很不错
They say he's one of the best. But a really nice guy.
好  那就好
Good. That's good.
布鲁斯  我能怎么帮你
Bruce, what can I do to help you?
我需要个地方睡几晚
I could use a bed for a few nights.
你睡楼上的空房间吧
You can have the spare room upstairs.
那就太好了
That'd be so great.
还有件事
There is one other thing.
借过  抱歉
Excuse me. Pardon me.
借过
Coming through.
哥们  给五楼送的外卖
Hey, pal I got a delivery on five.
楼上应该没人
I don't think there's anybody up there.
老天
Oh, man.
我要是拿不到钱要倒大霉的  让我去试试吧
I'm gonna catch hell if I don't collect. You got to let me try.
这样吧  我这里多了份中号的  送你了
I'll tell you what. I got an extra medium. Take it on the house.
你最棒了
You are the man.
保佑你  哥们
God bless you, brother.
好啊
All right.
伊丽莎白·罗斯博士
好
Okay.
伽马脉冲
无匹配
B·班纳
登录远程聊天
加密中
呼叫 蓝先生
绿先生!
搜寻得如何?
数据被删了
如果没有数据
我就无法帮忙
那现在怎么办
我不能停留
我们已经关门了  各位  抱歉
We're pretty well closed here, folks. I'm sorry.
拜托  斯坦  今天周五
Oh, come on, Stan. It's Friday night.
孩子们
Oh, kids.
我现在只有海员沙司
I got nothing but marinara now.
我一定要来杯粉先生  拜托了
I got to have a mister pink, please.
她又忙得忘吃晚饭了
She worked through dinner again, of course.
斯坦
Stan?
然后他...我说  "好吧  你去哪了
And he... I go, "So, yeah, I mean, where were you?
我不知道你去哪了  西塞尔"
"I can't... I don't know where you were, Cecil."
他说  "没在你去的地方"
And he goes, "Not where you been at."
我想  "天呐"  我觉得好过意不去
I thought "Oh, my god." I just feIt so awfuI.
布鲁斯
Bruce?
贝蒂
Betty?
怎么了
What's going on?
贝蒂
Betty...
告诉我  我是不是真看见了他
Just tell me if I saw what I think I saw.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
求你  告诉我实话
Please, just tell me the truth.
别走
Don't go.
跟我走吧
I want you to come with me now.
求你  跟我走
Please. Come with me.
求你
Please.
这是我们的数据
It's our data.
我趁他们搬走前拿到的
I got in there before they carted it all away.
我希望或许哪天  它终能给我们答案
I hoped somewhere that it might tell us something someday.
将军知道你有这个吗
Does the general know that you have this?
不  应该不知道
No, I don't think so.
我好几年没跟他说过话了
I haven't spoken to him in a couple of years.
你一定要确定
You have to be sure.
布鲁斯
Bruce,
我不明白我们为什么不能直接去找他
I don't understand why we can't just go in there together
跟他谈
and talk to him.
他告诉了我  他想做什么
He told me what he wanted to do.
他想把它从我身体里弄出来
He wants it out of me.
肢解它  然后好加以复制
He wants to dissect it so that he can replicate it.
他想把它变成武器
He wants to make it a weapon.
低温恒温罐  斯塔克工业
你或许会想...
I thought you might want to...
谢谢
Thanks.
我该尽早离开  越早越好
Listen, I should leave early, as early as I can.
真的
Really?
你不能留几天吗
You can't stay at all?
我想  但我在这里实在不安全
I want to, but it's just not safe for me to be here.
-能借我点钱的话  -没问题
- If I could borrow some cash... - Of course.
我得坐大巴
I need to take a bus.
至少让我送你去车站
Well, at least let me walk you to the station.
好
Okay.
不缺什么了吧
You have everything you need?
嗯
Yeah.
我
I...
怎么了
What?
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
好好休息吧
I hope you get some rest.
我们只给你注射很低的剂量
We're giving you a very low dose only.
我需要你保持敏锐和纪律
I need you sharp out there and disciplined.
如果出现任何副作用
First sign of any side effect,
就中止  你也要离队  直到摆脱影响
we stop and you're off team until you straighten out.
同意吗
Agreed?
同意
Agreed.
你要进行两次注射
You'll get two separate infusions.
一次注入深层肌肉  一次注入骨髓中心
One into the deep muscle, one into the bone marrow centers.
入骨的那针会疼的
The bone ones are going to hurt.
没事吧
Is everything okay?
应该没事
I think so.
过来
Come here.
我就是想这样
I just wanna do this.
这样更好看
It's better like that.
是吗
Yeah?
太紧了  是吧
It feels too tight, huh?
-有点  -好
- Yeah, a little. - Okay.
怎么了
What?
他们来了
They're here.
-贝蒂  看着我  -布鲁斯
- Betty, look at me, look at me! - Bruce!
你得有多远跑多远
You have to go far away from me as you can!
-别跟我争  快走  -布鲁斯
- Don't argue with me, just go. Go! - Bruce!
该死  我们再过三分钟就能安排好狙击手了
Damn it! We'd have had snipers on target in three more minutes.
是谁着急了
I wanna know who jumped the gun.
他前进方向270
He's heading 2-7-0.
布朗斯基  别急
Blonsky! Not yet!
是  长官
Sir.
精神点  场面可能会变得很有趣
Look alive. This could get interesting.
我看到他了
I got him!
停下
Stop!
我知道你在里面
I know you're in there!
将军  求你
General, please!
长官
Sir?
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  别这样
Dad, please don't do this.
你在这事上看不清楚  给我进去
You can't see this clearly. Now, get inside.
他在那里
There he is!
目标在天桥上  我们看到他了
Target is in the overpass. We have a visual.
不要与他接触  重复  不要与他接触
Do not engage! Repeat, do not engage!
他被包围了
He's locked in.
打两罐催泪瓦斯进去
Put two canisters in there with him.
开火
Fire!
把她拉回来
Get her back here!
这下她会看清了
Now she'll see.
A队
Alpha team?
全力攻击
Let him have all of it.
开火
Come on, light him up!
.50的枪呢  快过来
Where are the fifty cals? Move your asses!
天呐
Oh, my god!
布朗斯基  你上
Blonsky, now you're up!
长官
Sir?
掩护我
Cover me.
记得我吗
Remember me?
天呐  他真行
My god, he's doing it.
把他引到大炮附近
Move him toward the cannons!
快走
Move!
保持位置
Hold your position!
开始
Do it now!
求你  不要
Please, please, please, no!
-求你  不要  -把她拉开
- Please, please, please! - Get her back!
你要杀死他了
You're killing him!
停下  放开我
Stop! Get off of me!
布鲁斯
Bruce!
武装直升机呢
Where's the gunship?
这就完了
Is that it?
布朗斯基  马上撤
Blonsky, pull back now.
撤
Pull back!
你就这点本事了吗
Is that all you got?
撤
Fall back!
-撤  -我们走
- Fall back! - Let's go, let's go!
找掩护
Find cover!
贝蒂
Betty!
开火  该死
Fire, goddamn it!
布鲁斯
Bruce?
停火
Stop firing!
不
No!
你做得对  打给我们
You did the right thing, calling us.
我需要知道他们要去哪
I need to know where they're going.
只要她跟他在一起  就会非常危险
She'll be in incredible danger as long as she's with him.
谁对她有危险
From who?
他保护了她  而你差点害死她
He protected her. You almost killed her.
我保证  她的安全是我现在的首要考虑
I give you my word, her safety is my main concern at this point.
知道吗  我有一项职业的骄傲
You know, it's a point of professional pride with me
就是总能分辨出谎言
that I can always tell when somebody's lying.
你就在撒谎
And you are.
我不知道他要去哪
I don't know where he's going.
我知道如果她能  就会帮他
I know she'll help him, if she can.
那她就是在协助逃犯
Then she's aiding a fugitive.
那我就帮不了他俩了
And I can't help either one of them.
我以前还不明白她为什么从不谈起你
I used to wonder why she never talked about you.
现在我知道了
Now I know!
她是从哪认识的这些家伙
Where does she meet these guys?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
Bruce.
没事的  没事
It's okay. It's okay.
过来  到这边来
Come here. Come this way.
小心头
Watch your head.
我们没事的
We're okay.
没事的
It's okay.
只是下雨而已
It's just the rain.
他还能再走路吗
Will he ever walk again?
他身体里的大部分骨头现在都像碾碎的石头了
Most of the bones in his body look like crushed gravel right now.
我要承认  他的心脏像机器一样
I will say this for him. He's got a heart like a machine.
除了赛马  还从未见过这样的
Never seen anything like it, outside of a racehorse.
来
Here.
好了
Okay.
布鲁斯
Bruce?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
嗯  我感觉好多了
Yeah, actually, I feel a lot better.
-很好  -我得把数据吐出来
- Good. - I just had to get my data back.
你把它吞下去了
You ate it?
是啊
Well, you know,
当时的情况得随机应变嘛
the circumstances called for a little improvisation.
他们的选择并不多
Okay, so they didn't have a great selection,
但我还是买了几件供你选
but I got you some options.
但首先
First thing's first.
不是吧
Oh, you're kidding me.
怎么了
What?
不要
No.
这是他们弹力最大的裤子了
They were the stretchiest pair they had.
我宁可碰运气
I'll take my chances.
卡弗大学事件
关于今天早些时候
Rumors continue to swirl about a violent clash
美国军队与不明敌人在卡弗大学校园内
between forces of the us military and an unknown adversary
发生激烈冲突的谣传仍甚嚣尘上
on the campus of Culver University earlier today.
二年级学生杰克·麦吉
Sophomores Jack McGee and
和吉姆·威尔逊见证了部分战斗场面
Jim Wilson witnessed some of the battle.
它好大
It was so big.
-特别巨大  庞然大物[浩克]  -嗯
- It was like this huge, like, hulk! - Yeah.
麦吉碰巧是校报的记者
McGee, who happens to be a reporter for the campus paper,
用手机拍下了这幅画面
captured this on his cell phone.
进一步对神秘"浩克"的搜索
Further search for the mysterious "Hulk"
卡弗大学事件
因烟山国家公园的
was postponed by powerful thunderstorms
超强雷暴而被迫推迟
in the smoky mountain national forest.
汽车旅馆
后面别剪太短了
Not too short back there.
我以前剪过的
I have done this before, you know.
真不知你这么久以来是怎么自己剪的
I don't know how you've done this on your own for all this time.
一般是用大剪刀
With clippers, usually.
-等等  -怎么了
- Wait, wait, wait. Wait. - What? What?
我们不能这么做
We can't do this.
-没事  我想的  -不
- It's okay. I want to. - No.
不行
No.
我不能
I can't.
我不能太激动
I can't get too excited.
一点点也不行吗
Not even a little excited?
没事的
It's okay.
长官  是布朗斯基
Sir, it's Blonsky.
有人去查过他有没有亲属家人什么的吗
Has anyone found out if he has next of kin or family?
您自己问他吧
Ask him yourself.
长官
Sir?
很高兴你恢复过来了  士兵
Good to see you back on your feet, soldier.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
你感觉如何
How do you feel?
很不爽  准备打第三轮了
Pissed off and ready for round three.
简单说  这些我们都不能用
Basically, we can't use any of this,
因为都可以被追踪
because they can track all of it.
那我的唇膏呢  也能被追踪吗
Well, my lip gloss? Can they track that?
不  你可以拿着你的唇膏
No. You can take your lip gloss.
谢谢
Thank you.
我还需要我的眼镜
Well, I need my glasses.
你的眼镜和
Well, you can take your glasses
-手表可以拿  -好
- and your watch, okay? - Okay.
大部分都还能用
We can use most of it.
但是不能用信用卡  身份证和手机
We just can't use the credit cards, the ID or the phone.
-打都不要打开  -好
- Don't even turn that on. - Okay.
现金也要拿着
And we'll take the cash, obviously.
只靠40美元  不用信用卡
How will we get where we need to go
我们怎么能到目的地
on $40 and no credit cards?
我们可以卖了这个
Well, we could sell this.
不  你只有这一个她的遗物了  不行
No. No, that's the only thing you have left from her. No.
那我们就想办法再赎回来
Well, we'll have to try and get it back.
联邦机构已经在监控电话
Federal is already monitoring phones,
卡  和罗斯博士的网络账户
plastic and Dr. Ross's web accounts,
当地警方也对他们发出了通告
and local pd have been placed on alert.
他们总会冒头的  到时候
They'll pop up somewhere and when they do,
我们就会马上知道
it comes straight to us.
他们不会冒头的
They're not gonna just pop up.
他撑了五年
He made it five years and
还跨越了国境  从不曾出错
got across borders without making any mistakes.
他不会现在开始用信用卡的
He's not gonna use a damn credit card now.
如果他想跑  那他早就跑了
If he was trying to escape, he'd be long gone.
他这次没想跑
He's not trying to escape this time.
他在寻求帮助  我们就这么抓住他
He's looking for help and that's how we're gonna get him.
我们知道他们想要什么
We know what they're after
我们知道他跟一个人有联络
and we know he's been talking to somebody.
你们都拿到了通讯记录的副本
You all have copies of the correspondence.
绿先生和蓝先生的假名
The aliases Mr. Green and Mr. Blue
来自绿先生的文件
已被加入了神盾局行动数据库
have been added to the SHIELD operations database.
蓝先生  数据在这里
如果他冒头了  我们会等着他的
If he comes up for air, we'll be waiting.
该见面了
绿先生
如果他出了声  我们会听到的
If he makes a peep, we'll hear him.
等他出了错  我们会准备就绪
And when he slips up, we'll be ready.
神盾局
来自绿先生的文件
蓝先生  数据在这里  该见面了
绿先生
格雷伯恩大学
细胞生物学部
塞缪尔·史登博士
找到匹配
纽约市
格雷伯恩大学
待售
笑一个
Smile.
那是什么感觉
What is it like?
发生的时候  你有什么体验
When it happens, what do you experience?
记得我们在哈佛志愿接受的实验吗
Remember those experiments we volunteered for at Harvard?
诱发幻觉的
Those induced hallucinations?
很像那个  但放大了一千倍
It's a lot like that, just a thousand times amplified.
就像有人往我脑子里倒了一升酸液
It's like someone's poured a liter of acid into my brain.
你记得任何事吗
Do you remember anything?
只有碎片  图像
Just fragments. Images.
杂音太多  我无法从中得到什么
There's too much noise. I can never derive anything out of it.
但还是你在里面啊
But then it's still you inside it.
不  不是的
No. No, it's not.
我不知道  在洞里时  我真觉得它认识我
I don't know. In the cave, I really felt like it knew me.
或许你的心智还在其中
Maybe your mind is in there,
但被过载了  无法处理发生的情况
it's just overcharged and can't process what's happening.
我不想控制它  我想摆脱它
I don't want to control it. I want to get rid of it.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
我们来拉平差距吧
Let's even the playing field a little.
先生们
Gentlemen.
布鲁斯  醒醒
Bruce, wake up.
有情况
There's something going on.
准备停车
前方施工
我们得走了  走到后面去  别走太快
We got to go. Walk toward the back. Just don't move too fast.
好  来
All right. Come.
去上城区好远啊
It is a long way uptown.
坐地铁可能最快
I think the subway's probably quickest.
我在钢管里  还在地下深处
Me in a metal tube, deep underground,
身边是最暴戾的城市里的几百个人
with hundreds of people in the most aggressive city in the world?
是啊  我们打车吧
Right. Let's get a cab.
快点啊  你太慢了  开车像个娘们
Come on, now! Let's go! You're too slow! You drive like a woman!
-好啊  看到她了吗  -老天
- Very nice. You see her? - Oh, my.
真漂亮  小心着点  小子
Very pretty. Watch out, you goat!
呼吸  呼吸
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
你是疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
-你什么毛病  -怎么了  美女
- What is wrong with you? - What's the matter, baby?
不喜欢飞车吗
You don't like a good ride?
混蛋
Asshole!
我知道些技巧能帮你
You know, I know a few techniques could help you
有效地控制怒气
manage that anger very effectively.
闭嘴  我们走路
You zip it. We're walking.
好
Okay.
打扰  史登博士吗
Excuse me. Dr. Sterns?
-是  -抱歉打扰你
- Yes. - I'm sorry to bother you.
我是伊丽莎白·罗斯
I'm Elizabeth Ross.
罗斯博士
Dr. Ross!
我带来个人  他想见见你
I have someone who'd like to meet you.
好吧
Okay.
你是蓝先生吧
It's Mr. Blue, isn't it?
绿先生吗
Mr. Green?
我得告诉你  我还怀疑你是不是真的
I got to tell you, I've been wondering if you were even real.
如果你是  那会是什么样
And if you were, what would it look like?
一个体内有那么强大力量的人
A person with that much power lurking in him.
我真是万万没想到
Nothing could have surprised me more
会是这么低调的人  跑来跟我握手
than this unassuming man shaking my hand.
但是  这可不是什么简单的小事
But, look. We're not strolling into the park for a picnic, here.
就算一切顺利
Even if everything goes perfectly,
我们诱发了发作  并且准确调对了剂量
if we induce an episode, if we get the dosage exactly right,
那是能彻底治愈你
is that going to be a lasting cure
还是会成为一种解药  来抑制爆发
or just some antidote to suppress that specific flare-up?
我也不知道
I don't know.
我是说
What I'm saying is that
如果我们稍有偏差
if we overshoot this by even the smallest integer
这种浓缩物
we're dealing with concentrations
可是毒性极强的
with extraordinary levels of toxicity.
你是说他可能因此而死
You mean it could kill him.
死  没错
Kill him? Yeah.
可以这么说吧
I should say so.
你要知道  还有另一方面的忧虑
You should know that there's a flip side to this, too.
如果剂量不够
If we miss on the low side,
如果诱发了发作  却不能控制
if we induce me and it fails,
那对你可就相当危险了
this will be very dangerous for you.
听着  我一向是好奇大于谨慎
Look. I've always been more curious than cautious,
这对我来说挺好的
and that's served me pretty well.
所以  我们还做不做了
So, are we going to do this?
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling, man?
像个野兽
Like a monster.
好了  上去
Okay. On the table.
如果你反应激烈
These will protect you from yourself
这会保证你不会伤到自己
if you have a strong reaction.
你回头再告诉我你觉得反应激不激烈吧
You can tell me later if you thought it was strong.
拜托  该死的蠢研究生
Oh, come on! Stupid graduate students.
好吧
Okay...
你  你  你
You, you, you.
这会是种新鲜的感觉
This will be a somewhat novel sensation.
开始了
We have begun.
透析机会把解药跟你的血混合起来
The dialysis machine will mix the antidote with your blood.
但只有达到完全发作
Except the antidote will only take hold
解药才会生效
once we've achieved a full reaction.
放松
Just relax.
好了  准备就绪
Okay. We are comprehensive.
给
Here you go.
好  可以开始了吗
All right. We set to pop?
你最好别握着他了
I'd take your hands off him.
天呐
Oh, my god!
等等  还没完  等等
Wait, wait! There's more! Wait!
-好了  -等等
- Now. Okay, now! - Wait.
动手吧
Now, do it!
开始
Do it!
布鲁斯  布鲁斯  看着我
Bruce! Bruce, look at me.
坚持住  解药  快
Stay with me. The antidote, now!
史登  快开始
Sterns, do it now!
布鲁斯  看着我  看着我的眼睛
Bruce, look at me. Look in my eyes.
请看着我的眼睛
Please, look in my eyes.
开什么玩笑
Oh, you've got to be kidding me!
布鲁斯
Bruce.
天呐
Oh, my god.
布鲁斯
Bruce?
布鲁斯  听得到吗
Bruce, can you hear me?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
没事了
It's okay.
你没事了
You're okay.
你做到了
You did it.
他没事  这太了不起了
He's fine. This is fantastic.
结束了
It's over.
那真是我这辈子见过的
That was the most extraordinary thing
最了不起的事了
I have seen in my entire life!
好了  停下吧  拜托
Okay, you know what? Stop, please.
我们得谈谈刚刚发生的事
We need to go back and talk about what just happened in there.
当然  好
Absolutely. Okay.
伽马脉冲来自杏仁核
The gamma pulse came from the amygdala.
-我觉得罗斯博士的引物  -你没事吧
- I think Dr. Ross's primer... - Are you okay?
让细胞暂时吸收了能量
...lets the cells absorb the energy temporarily,
然后它就消退了
and then it abates.
所以你多年前才没有死于辐射中毒
That's why you didn't die of radiation sickness years ago!
或许我们已经永久性地中和了细胞
Now, maybe we've neutralized those cells permanently,
也可能是抑制了爆发
or maybe we just suppressed that event.
我偏向于认为是后者  但很难确定
I'm inclined to think the latter, but it's hard to know
因为我们的测试对象都没活下来过
because none of our test subjects ever survived.
-当然了  他们没有引物  -等等
- Of course, they weren't getting the primer! - Wait, wait. Wait,
你刚刚说什么
what did you just say?
他们没注射肌肉生长抑制素引物
They weren't getting the myostatin primer...
不不  测试对象
No, no, no. Test subjects?
什么测试对象
What test subjects?
跟我来
Come with me.
活动等级如何
What's the activity level?
狙击手覆盖了A区
Snipers are covering Alpha sector.
我们首先拿老鼠做实验
We started on rats and mice,
但它们都完全被烤死了
but it just completely fried them,
所以我们只能拿更大的东西实验
so we had to go bigger.
我们仍不知道哪个毒性更大
And we still don't know which is more toxic,
伽马射线  还是你的血
the gamma or your blood.
什么意思  我的血
What do you mean, my blood?
布鲁斯  这都是你
Bruce, this is all you.
绿先生
批号: 7754
强度: 1.08%
你寄来的不够我研究
You didn't send me much to work with,
我只好浓缩复制了
so I had to concentrate it and make more.
虽然经过了一番试错
With a little more trial and error,
但前途无可限量
there's no end to what we can do!
这可是潜力无量
This is potentially olympian!
这种伽马科技用途无限
This gamma technology has limitless applications.
我们能制造数百种解药
We'll unlock hundreds of cures.
我们能让人类不怕疾病
We will make humans impervious to disease!
不不  我们得销毁它
No, no, we've got to destroy it.
-等等  什么  -全部的
- Wait, what? - All of it.
就今晚  全部焚毁
Tonight. We're gonna incinerate it.
-所有的都在这里吗  -什么
- Is this the whole supply? - What...
我们可以凭这个拿诺贝尔奖呢
We could get the nobel for this!
你不理解这玩意的威力
You don't understand the power of this thing.
太危险了  不可控制
It is too dangerous. It cannot be controlled.
酌情处理  枪手
At your discretion, shooter.
我们三个
...three of us!
-这是普罗米修斯之火  -这是...
- This is Promethean fire! - It's just...
无法射击
No shot.
布朗斯基进去了
Blonsky's going in.
布朗斯基  退下  我女儿还在里面
Blonsky, stand down. My daughter's in there!
我们有解药了
We have the antidote now.
他们要的不是解药
They don't want the antidote!
他们要把它制成武器
They want to make it a weapon!
如果我们放走它  就永远别想追回来了
And if we let it go, we will never get it back.
你根本不知道这玩意多强大
You don't know how powerful this thing is.
我跟别人一样痛恨政府
I hate the government just as much as anyone,
但你太多疑了吧
but you're being a little paranoid, don't you think?
布鲁斯  布鲁斯
Bruce! Bruce!
出去
Get out.
它在哪  出来啊  它在哪
Where is it? Come on, where is it?
让他出来见我
Show him to me.
布朗斯基
Blonsky!
小姐
Miss!
披上吧
Take this.
如果你夺走了它
If you took it from me,
我就让你在牢里关一辈子
I'm gonna put you in a hole for the rest of your life.
贝蒂
Betty.
我永远不会原谅你对他做的事
I will never forgive what you've done to him.
他是个逃犯
He's a fugitive.
那是你害的
You made him a fugitive
好掩盖你的失败  保护你的事业
to cover your failures and to protect your career.
永远别再把我当作你女儿了
Don't ever speak to me as your daughter again.
就是因为你是我女儿
It's only because you're my daughter
才没有也被铐起来
that you're not in handcuffs, too.
你是说你可以制造更多他那样的人吗
Are you telling me you can make more like him?
现在还不能  我是有一些碎片
No! Not yet. I sorted out a few pieces,
但我并不能再组装出一个大怪物来
but it's not like I can put together the same humpty dumpty,
如果你是这个意思
if that's what you're asking.
他是个意外事故  目标是做得更好
He was a freak accident! The goal is to do it better!
那么班纳是唯一
So Banner's the only...
她真是个烦人的贱人
She's an annoying bitch.
你为什么总打人
Why are you always hitting people?
我做了什么  你要这么粗暴地对待我
Now what possibly could I have done to deserve such aggression?
不是你做了什么  是你要做什么
It's not what you've done. It's what you're gonna do.
我要你从班纳体内去掉的那东西
I want what you got out of Banner. I want that.
看上去
You look like
你体内已经注射了点什么了  是吧
you've got a little something in you already, don't you?
我还要更多
I want more.
你看到他会变成什么了  是吧
You've seen what he becomes, right?
是啊
I have
它好美
and it's beautiful.
像神一般
Godlike.
我要那个
Well, I want that.
我需要那个  把我变成那个
I need that. Make me that.
我不知道你已经注射了什么
I don't know what you've got inside you already.
混合的产物可能会
The mix could be
令人憎恶
an abomination.
我没说我不愿意
I didn't say I was unwilling.
我只是需要你知情同意
I just need informed consent.
你同意了
And you've given it.
绿先生批号: 2058
强度: 14.56%
我之前就是说这个
This is what I was trying to explain.
我不知道你已经注射了什么
I don't know what you've been ladling into yourself.
但显然  很成功
But clearly it worked.
你大概是完全听不懂我的话吧
Let's assume you don't understand a word I'm saying,
但麻烦你回到桌子上
but if you'll just get back on the table,
我可以修复你
I can fix this.
开枪
Shoot it!
不
No!
D4呼叫指挥
Delta 4 to leader.
他们干掉了我们两个人  两个人
They took out two of our guys, two of our guys!
布朗斯基和少校还在里面
Blonsky and the major are still inside!
走  上上上
Come on! Move, move, move, move!
在那里
It's over there!
干掉他们
Drop them!
-那是什么  -开枪
- What is that thing? - Shoot it!
好吧  你开车  我们走  走
Okay. All right! You... you, drive! Let's go! Move, move!
-D4呼叫指挥  -快走
- Delta 4 to leader! - Go, go, go, go, go!
这里出现了什么大家伙
Something big just went off down here!
将军  您该来听听
General, you should hear this!
浩克在街上  重复  浩克在街上
The hulk is in the street! I repeat, the hulk is in the street!
不可能  你镇定下来  年轻人
That's impossible. You get a hold of yourself, young man.
振作起来  你在什么位置
You get it together. What is your position?
121街  沿百老汇向北
121st street, heading north on Broadway!
调头
Turn us around.
我们回去了  为什么要回去
We're going back. Why are we going back?
该死  让我看下面的情况
Damn it! Give me eyes down there!
是  长官
Yes, sir!
那是什么玩意
What the hell was that?
快走
Go, go, go!
不
No!
你们的吗
One of yours?
天呐
Oh, my god.
你做了什么
What have you done?
开火  冲他开火
Fire at him, fire at him!
你觉得来福枪能打伤那玩意吗
Do you think a rifle's gonna hurt that?
来吧
Come on!
太棒了
Sweet.
看我的
Booyah!
快走  士兵
Get out of there, soldier!
斯黛茜
Stacy!
给我找个好对手来
Give me a real fight!
长官
Sir?
叫他们带所有武器前往哈莱姆
Tell them to bring everything they've got and head for Harlem.
必须我去
It has to be me.
你得带我回去
You have to take me back there.
你说什么呢
What are you saying?
你觉得你能控制它吗
You think you can control it?
不是控制它
No, no, not control it, but,
我说不好  或许让它针对打击
I don't know, maybe aim it.
如果你做不到呢
And what if you can't?
我们制造了这玩意
We made this thing.
我们所有人
All of us.
拜托了
Please.
-降落在附近  -不  保持高度
- Land us near it. - No, no. No, keep us high.
打开后门
Open the back door.
布鲁斯  布鲁斯  停下
Bruce! Bruce, stop!
停下  你在干什么
Stop! What are you doing?
想清楚了  你都不知道你能不能变身
Think about this! You don't even know if you'll change!
你不用这么做的  求你  这简直疯了
You don't have to do this! Please, this is insane!
贝蒂  我必须试试
Betty, I've got to try.
对不起
I'm sorry.
该死
Oh, shit!
把她拉回来
Get her in here!
来吧  小姐
Come on, miss.
出来了  贝蒂
There. Betty!
浩克
Hulk!
好啊
Yeah!
来吧
Come on!
你就这点本事吗
Is that all you've got?
开火啊  士兵  帮帮他
Use that thing, soldier! Give him some help!
哪个
Which one?
帮绿的那个  该死  你以为呢
Help the green one, damn it! Which one do you think?
把另一个撕碎了
Cut the other one in half!
罗斯
Ross!
继续扫射
Keep it on him!
-我得降落了  -把住
- Look, I got to put it down! - Hang on!
爸爸
Dad?
你受伤了吗  让我帮你
Are you hurt? Let me help you.
我没事  你找条路出去
I'm all right. Just find a way out.
你不配拥有这份力量
You don't deserve this power!
看着她死吧
Now watch her die!
小心
Look out!
将军
General?
有什么遗言吗
Any last words?
浩克砸
Hulk smash!
停下
Stop!
没事了
It's okay.
贝蒂
Betty.
电量低
英属哥伦比亚贝拉库拉
贝蒂·罗斯  卡弗大学
无事故天数
再来
Reload.
旧啤酒和失败的气味
The smell of stale beer and defeat.
我也不想说"早告诉你了"  将军
You know, I hate to say, "I told you so," General,
但超级士兵项目被搁置是有原因的
but that super soldier program was put on ice for a reason.
我一直觉得硬件更可靠
I've always felt hardware was more reliable.
斯塔克
Stark.
将军
General.
你穿的东西一向高级
You always wear such nice suits.
说得太对了
Touché.
听说你有个不一般的问题
I hear you have an unusual problem.
你还好意思说
You should talk.
你该听听
You should listen.
如果我告诉你我们在组建一支队伍呢
What if I told you we were putting a team together?
"我们"是谁
Who's "we"?